RICARDO CESAR MALDONADO ALONSO

400 Scarborough Cir, Corona CA 92879 | Phone: 714-785-4205 | rcmalonso@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/DestroNic

Objective

Problem-solving, versatile, passionate Web Developer looking for an opportunity to be part of a development team, been in web development since 2016, worked for short term projects and now I'm looking for employment to turn my passion into my career.

Skills

• Design and prototype: Figma, VSCode

• Front-end: React, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery.

• Back-end: PHP, Python, Node.js

• Database: MongoDB, MySQL.

• Other: Git version control, Postman, MySQL workbench.

Experience

Developer (Contractor)

June 2021 to Present

Serix LLC – New York, NY

Work remotely adding and modifying features to a POS software (www.sambapos.com), features are built in JavaScript and I use node.js for the backend, graphQL for queries and SQL as database, I'm currently working as a contractor but I'm looking for an opportunity in a full time position.

Customer Service

May 2019 to October 2021

Bank of America – Brea, CA

Help Customer with issues regarding their account and online banking, also help customer with letters or documents requests

IT services

Jul 2017 to May 2019

Self Employed – Corona, CA

IT services such as information recovery/backup, hardware setup, configuration, troubleshooting and software installation, computer repair and upgrade, networking, remote assistance, active directory, DHCP, DNS

Education and Training

Fullstack Web Development

October 2019 - October 2020

Bottega Coding Bootcamp

Systems Engineering

2003 - 2006

Universidad de Ciencia y Tecnologia (UCYT) Managua, Nicaragua – I did 3 years of college.

Personal References

April Turner - Canyon Lake Med Spa - Client Phone: (951) 837-6977

Walter Murillo - Former Co-worker Phone: (310) 803-4936

Mike Marchese - Client Phone: (818) 397-7171

Alba Luz Ortega - Client Phone: (951) 271-2068

Projects

California Liver Research Institute

This project was built in plain HTML, CSS and Javascript, I used some libraries such as

CSS animate, Jquery and Font Awesome, the website is fully mobile responsive. Project URL: https://www.caliverresearch.org/

Pasadena Liver Center

This project was built in React.JS and SCSS, the website is fully mobile responsive. Project URL: https://www.pasadenalivercenter.com/

MPH Tech Inc.

This project was built with HTML, CSS and JavaScript, website fully responsive. Project URL: https://www.mphtechinc.com/